# BABONGILE THANDOLWENKOSI NYONI

Zimbabwe (Willing to relocate) +263786364959 •babongiletnyoni@gmail.com

### **Professional Profile**

A qualified and compassionate Care assistant with over 3 years of experience, working in both home and clinical setting. With excellent verbal and written skills, passion for personal development and commitment to patients' comfort and safety. Taking pride in maintaining their privacy and confidentiality.

## **Skills and Attributes**

- Outstanding skills in coordinating with other professional staff
- Compassionate
- Observant
- Interpersonal skills
- Risk Assessment
- Records management
- Wound dressing
- Vital observations
- Catheter care
- Pressure Area Care
- Excellent communication skills
- Safe Patient handling
- Excellent driving skills

# **Work Experience**

#### CARE ASSISTANT, NAZARETH HOUSE

January 2023-Present

- Providing personal care such as bathing, dressing and undressing, oral care and hair grooming.
- Assisting with toileting.
- Manual handling using devices like the walking frames, wheelchairs and Mo-lift.
- Performing light household duties and assisting with feeding
- Administering medication according to the MAR sheet.
- Meal preparation.
- Maintaining a daily journal and reporting any physical or cognitive changes.
- Spending time with the clients, including reading to them, watching TV and having conversations.
- Offering emotional support, companionship and having conversations.

#### **Health Care Assistant**

March 2022-January 2023

PARIRENYATWA GROUP OF HOSPITALS

- Bed making and bed bathing patients.
- Feeding patients.
- Pressure area care and catheter care.
- Assisting with elimination.
- Performing routine clinical duties such as damp dusting, data entry, answering telephones and assisting customers.
- Maintained Infection, prevention and control measures.
- Escorting patients to doctor's appointments.
- Reported to the nurses any changes noted in the patients.

#### **Community Care Worker**

Voluntary work at Ekuphumuleni Home

April 2020-March 2022

- Looked after elderly patients.
- Provided companionship.
- Meal preparation.
- Assisting the elderly with feeding, bathing, dressing and undressing.
- Took the clients for walks and had conversations with them.
- Cleaning and making the clients' beds.

## **Education**

# NURSE AID AND FIRST AID Zimbabwe Red Cross Society Diploma In General Nursing Parirenyatwa School of Nursing Ordinary Level 2022

# Other documents

Sizane High School

International Driving license (class 4)